# **Richard Grunert**

Full-Stack Web Developer // Android Developer // Linux Administrator

# **Objective**

To utilize my vast range of skills to write amazing and beautiful code, and to further improve my overall skillset by learning from other developers.

#### **About Me**

Computers are my passion; I've been working with them daily since I was a small child and am always improving my skills. I learn things I'm interested in very quickly, and nothing interests me more than computer systems and software development. I've worked with a wide range of systems and languages, and can adapt very quickly to new ones I might need to learn on the fly.

I've built \$20,000 websites for attorneys, developed my own software and am a huge Linux aficionado (though I also work daily with Windows and OSX systems). I run my own servers for fun, build websites from scratch and co-administrate a website that gets around 30,000 hits daily from all over the US. I prefer to write software using functional programming conventions, but I'm also well-versed in the Object-Oriented style.

In 2015 I led a team that developed and published Lunar Invasion, a game for Android smartphones that's currently available on the Google Play Store. I'm also a published writer.

You can see examples of my projects at my personal website: http://furu.guru.

# **Technologies**

I know too many to list here. The following list is only a sample.

- **➡** Git
- Maven / Gradle
- Nginx / Apache
- **▶** Postgres / MySQL
- **▶** HTTPS (SSL)
- **⇒** jQuery
- → REST / XML / JSON
- Responsive Design
- Material Design (Android)

# **Experience**

Accident Data Center
Developer / Asst. Webmaster
2015 - Present

Brett Law
Web Developer
2014 - 2015

# Languages

Ordered by proficiency.

- Java
- **▶** Clojure (JVM Lisp)
- **▶** PHP
- → HTML / SCSS
- JavaScript
- Python
- C/C++
- SQL / SPARQL
- Shell Scripting
- ♦ 6502 ASM

# **Education**

Western Washington University BA in Journalism, Minor: Arabic 2009 - 2013

Contact: richard@furu.guru